Guide to the Vice President for Research and Advanced Studies records, 1961-1998.
Vice President for Research and Advanced Studies records, 1961-1998.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Vice President for Research and Advanced Studies records, 1961-1998.
4-5-1243
Cornell University. Office of the Vice President for Research and Advanced Studies.
17.4 cubic ft.
Records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes records concerning research and research proposals in various academic departments and study centers at Cornell University, including the Center for International Studies, the Center for Radiophysics and Space Research, and others; includes files of Franklin A. Long.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes records concerning research and research proposals in various academic departments and study centers at Cornell University, including the Center for International Studies, the Center for Radiophysics and Space Research, and others; includes files of Franklin A. Long.
Also, the records of the Assistant Vice President for Research and Outreach, Lucinda Noble. They include correspondence, reports, minutes, publications and subject files. This office existed from 1994-1998 with Norman Scott as the Director.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Office of the Vice President for Research and Advanced Studies.; Long, Franklin A., 1910-; Noble, Lucinda.; Scott, Norman.; Cornell University--Administration.; Cornell University. Center for International Studies.; Cornell University. Center for Radiophysics and Space Research.; Cornell University. Office of the Vice President for Research and Outreach.
Subjects:
Research--United States--Management.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of office of origin. (Box 8 not restricted)
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collection #4/5/1322 and #4/5/1590.
CONTAINER LIST
- Vice President for Research [W.D. Cooke] records, 1962-1970 (Collection #4-5-1590)
  - Cornell and its community - unfiled (Box 1)
  - Unlabelled file (Box 1)
  - Calendar - Univ. (Box 1)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Box 1)
  - China Program (Box 1)
  - Computer Science, Dept. of, CU (Box 1)
  - Computer - re: other colleges (Box 1)
  - Conflict of interest M (Box 1)
  - Consulting policy - CU (Box 1)
  - Cornell Research Grants Committee (Box 1)
  - Cost of education allowance (Box 1)
  - CU Newsletter (Box 1)
  - Cost sharing (Box 1)
  - Brewster proposal - cost sharing (Box 1)
  - Counsel, Univ. (Box 1)
  - Daddario, Emilio (Box 1)
  - Dean's meeting, minutes (Box 1)
  - Dept. of Defense (Box 1)
  - du Vigneaud, Vinc. - CU (Box 1)
  - Education: articles (Box 1)
  - Education, Dept. of (NYS) (Box 1)
  - Defense Education Act (INDEA) F (Box 1)
  - Educational Facilities Act F (Box 1)
  - Educational Policy Research Center (Box 1)
  - Educational Reseach and Development, Center for CU (Box 1)
  - Environmental Education Center (Box 1)
  - Exchange Program (Box 1)
  - Extension: general (Box 1)
  - Firearms, use at CU (Box 1)
  - Foundations: reports to JP (Box 1)
  - Effort reporting (Box 1)
  - Federal aid to education - general F (Box 1)
  - Higher Education Act of 1965 F (Box 1)
  - NFS news releases (Box 1)
  - NSF Senior Foreign Scientist Fellowship (Box 1)
  - NSF Institutional Grant F (Box 1)
  - National Medal of Science (Box 1)
  - Nepotism CU (Box 1)
  - Organization CU (Box 2)
  - Oak Ridge National Laboratory (Box 2)
  - Ornithology - general (Box 2)
  - Ornithology - budget and finance (Box 2)
  - Ornithology - Brewster Wing (Box 2)
  - Ornithology - A.A. Allen Memorial (Box 2)
  - Ornithology - minutes and reports (Box 2)
  - Overhead M (Box 2)
  - Parking CU (Box 2)
  - Peace Corps CU (Box 2)
  - Personnel CU (Box 2)
  - Personnel - job related courses (Box 2)
  - Policy - university general (Box 2)
  - Retirement (Box 2)
  - Planning Office CU (Box 2)
  - Political campaigns (Box 2)
  - Post-doctorals - general CU (Box 2)
  - Presidential candidates - 1968 (Box 2)
  - Private university support (Box 2)
  - Professors-at-large (Box 2)
  - Project Literacy (Harry Levin) CU (Box 2)
  - Public Affairs, Vice President for (Box 2)
  - Puerto Rico, University of M (Box 2)
  - Research sponsored (Box 2)
  - Regional Planning (Box 2)
  - Regional Resources and Development (Box 2)
  - Registration (Box 2)
  - Research - general (Box 2)
  - Research reports (Box 2)
  - Research: federal aid (Box 3)
  - Research on Healthy Humans (policy) (Box 3)
  - R and D Bulletins (Box 3)
  - Research Policy and Personnel (Comm.) (Box 3)
  - Research Policy and Personnel - minutes (Box 3)
  - Research Institute CU (Box 3)
  - Research Park CU (Box 3)
  - Research Park Reports (Box 3)
  - Aerial photography (Box 3)
  - Animal Research Facility (Box 3)
  - Enzyme Laboratory (Box 3)
  - Plasma research (CU-NRL) (Box 3)
  - Science and Tech. Foundation (NYS) (Box 3)
  - CRF - general (Box 3)
  - CRF - minutes (Box 3)
  - CRF - patents and trademarks (Box 3)
  - CRF - patents, affiliated interference (Box 4)
  - Rohm and Haas M (Box 4)
  - Routing and evaluation of proposals CU (Box 4)
  - Sabbatic leaves (Box 4)
  - Salaries: faculty: general (Box 4)
  - Salaries: Research Association (Box 4)
  - Salary recovery (Box 4)
  - Senator Goodell's Science Advisory Committee (Box 4)
  - Postdoctoral Teaching Program (NYS) (Box 4)
  - Distinguished Professor Visit. Prog. (NYS) S (Box 4)
  - Sciences articles: general (Box 4)
  - Security information (Box 4)
  - E.I. DuPont de Nemours & Co. S (Box 4)
  - Fellowships: corporate (m) (Box 4)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 4)
  - Foundation - miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - General Electric Foundation (Box 4)
  - Radio Corporation of America (Box 4)
  - Shell Companies Foundation (Box 4)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation (Box 4)
  - United States Rubber Company (Box 4)
  - United States Steel Foundation (Box 4)
  - United States Rubber Company (Box 4)
  - United States Steel Foundation (Box 4)
  - General Electric Co. M (Box 4)
  - Grants (corporate) (m) (Box 4)
  - Gun legislation (Box 4)
  - National Aeronautic & Space Administration F (Box 4)
  - General CU (Box 4)
  - NSF - general F (Box 4)
  - Human Affairs Program (Box 4)
  - Health, Education, and Welfare, Dept. of (Box 4)
  - Human Rights, Pres. Advisory Comm. CU (Box 5)
  - Human Rights - minutes (Box 5)
  - Humanities (Box 5)
  - Hypodermic equipment, NYS (Box 5)
  - IBM (Box 5)
  - Information systems (Box 5)
  - Institute for Science (Box 5)
  - Intercollege Compensation (policy) CU (Box 5)
  - International Education Act F (Box 5)
  - Intersession (Box 5)
  - Ithaca Neighborhood College (Box 5)
  - Latin American Program (Box 5)
  - Library - university (Box 5)
  - Multidisciplinary Research Program (Box 5)
  - Nat. Association of State Universities & Land Grant Colleges (Box 5)
  - National Institutes of Health (NIH) F (Box 5)
  - Biomedical Sciences Support Grant - 1967 (Box 5)
  - NSF - General II (Box 5)
  - Unfiled material, memoranda & research reports (Box 5)
  - Research statistics (1966-1967) (Box 5)
  - Long Annual Report 1965-1966, 1967-1968, 1966-1967 (Box 5)
  - CAL/CU 1967 (Box 5)
  - NASA, Management Organization Studies (Box 5)
  - NYSG&E "Bell" Plant (Box 5)
  - CRSR: Executive Committee (Box 5)
  - CRSR: NASA building (Box 6)
  - Cornell - Sydney Astronomy Center (Box 6)
  - Agriculture, College of (Box 6)
  - College of Agriculture - 1967 (Box 6)
  - Architecture, School of (Box 6)
  - Arts and Sciences, College of (Box 6)
  - Anthropology (Box 6)
  - Astronomy, Dept. of (Box 6)
  - Chemistry, Dept. of (cu) (Box 6)
  - Baker remodelling (Box 6)
  - School of Business and Public Administration (Box 6)
  - Engineering, College of (Box 6)
  - College of Human Ecology (Human Economics) (Box 6)
  - Hotel Administration, School of (Box 6)
  - Industrial and Labor Relations, School of (Box 6)
  - Electrical Eng. (Box 6)
  - Electron microscope (Siegel) (Box 6)
  - Plasma Studies, Laboratory for (Box 6)
  - Geological Sci., Dept. of CU (Box 6)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 6)
  - Graduate School I & II (Box 6)
  - Mathematics, Dept. of CU (Box 6)
  - Mathematics: Tax (Box 6)
  - Modern Languages, Division of CU (Box 6)
  - Nuclear Studies, Laboratory of (Box 6)
  - Physics, Dept. of CU (Box 6)
  - Atomic & Solid State Physics, Lab of (Box 6)
  - 10 Gev Synchrotron - general II (Box 6)
  - Psychology, Dept. of (Box 7)
  - Psychology, Liddel Laboratory (Box 7)
  - Social Sciences Building (Box 7)
  - Sociology (Box 7)
  - Division of Biological Sciences 1969 (Box 7)
  - Biological Sciences, Division of (Box 7)
  - Library, Biological Sciences (Box 7)
  - Biology, Langmuir (Box 7)
  - Biology: space and funding (Box 7)
  - Marine Biology and Oceanography - II (Box 7)
  - Mote Marine Lab (Box 7)
  - Myers Point (International Salt) (Box 7)
  - Biology: Wing Annex (Box 7)
  - Selective Service (Box 7)
  - Social Sciences: Hildebrand Comm. (Box 7)
  - Anthropology Study Comm. (Box 7)
  - Economics Study Comm. (Box 7)
  - Psychology Study Comm. (Box 7)
  - Sociology Study Comm. (Box 7)
  - Seven Universities (Box 7)
  - Southeast Asia Program (Box 7)
  - Soil, Water, Plant Relations Lab (Box 7)
  - Space: general (Box 7)
  - Space survey (Box 7)
  - State University of New York (SUNY) (Box 7)
  - Student Affairs, Vice President for (Box 7)
  - Summer Session (Box 8)
  - Sydney, University of (Box 8)
  - Teaching assistants (Box 8)
  - Technical Services Act (NY) (Box 8)
  - UCAR (Box 8)
  - Television (Box 8)
  - Universities Research Assoc. (Box 8)
  - Univ. Commission (Afro-American) (Box 8)
  - University reorganization (Box 8)
  - University - Rules & Regulations (Box 8)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Education (Box 8)
  - Univ. and Federal Government (Box 8)
  - Urban Studies Programs (Box 8)
  - VESIAC (Box 8)
  - Visiting professorships - general (Box 8)
  - Water supply CU (Box 8)
  - Zurn Foundation (Box 8)
  - Unfiled material: miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Medical College (Box 9)
  - Nutrition, School of (Box 9)
  - Nutrition, Analysis (Box 9)
  - Veterinary College (Box 9)
  - Accounting CU (Box 9)
  - Admissions CU (Box 9)
  - Advanced Research Projects Agency Fed (Box 9)
  - Agency for International Development Fed (Box 9)
  - Aid - Peru (W. Whyte) (Box 9)
  - Air Travel Institute cu (Box 9)
  - American Council on Education M (Box 9)
  - ACE - Committee on Sponsored Projects (Box 9)
  - Atomic Energy Commission Fed (Box 9)
  - American Society of International Law (Box 9)
  - Annual Reports (FAL) CU (Box 9)
  - Annual Reports - Coordinator of Research (Box 9)
  - Articles (Box 9)
  - Artificial Heart Program (Box 9)
  - B2 (Box 9)
  - Biology: Ecology, National Institute of (Box 9)
  - Board of Trustees (Box 9)
  - Budget - general CU (Box 9)
  - Budget - research (Box 9)
  - Computer Sciences 1964-1966 (Box 9)